Guide to the Lillian Hoban Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lillian Hoban papers
1950-2000
GEN MSS 1199
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
16.34
(84 boxes)
Hoban, Lillian, 1925-1998
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 83 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 84 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2013.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Papers and correspondence, circa 1950s-1980s. II. Writings and artwork, 1961-1997. III. Posters, circa 1970-1994. IV. Audiovisual materials, 1968-1994. V. Electronic media, circa 2000.
Lillian Hoban (1925-1998)
Lillian Hoban was an American illustrator and children's author.
Related Materials
Lillian Hoban Collection. Related materials: Russell Hoban Papers (GEN MSS 1436). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, drawings, posters, correspondence, other papers, and audiovisual materials. The writings and drawings document Lillian Hoban's career as a children's author and illustrator, including the Frances and Arthur books and her many collaborations with other authors including Miriam Cohen and Johanna Hurwitz. Audiovisual materials and born digital electronic media include interviews with Hoban and her then husband Russell Hoban.
Children's literature, American -- 20th Century; Illustration of books -- United States; Illustrators -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Illustrators -- United States -- 20th Century; Cohen, Miriam, 1926-; Hoban, Lillian, 1925-1998; Hoban, Russell, 1925-2011; Hurwitz, Johanna
- Papers and correspondence, circa 1950s-1980s; Series I; 1.08; (2 boxes)
  - Author of the Month Trumpet Club flyer and three posters., 1980s-1990s; cuid87; 2 folders (Box 2 (Oversize))
    Scope and Contents
    "Where Do The Animals Go When It Rains," "Everyone's Favorite First Grade," and Celebrate Children's book week with the Onondaga County Public Library; Meet Lillian.
  - Biographical note by Lillian Hoban for publication in Contemporary Authors, undated; cuid88 (Box 1)
  - Fan mail, 1990s-2000s; cuid89; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Frances birthday cards and Lillian Hoban memorial tribute invitation., circa 1990s, 1998; cuid90 (Box 1)
  - Francis party kit, circa 1990s; cuid91 (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Galley of "Mr. Pig and Sonny Too", 1977; cuid92 (Box 1)
  - Harper Collins printed biography flyers and bookmarks, 1977, undated; cuid93 (Box 1)
  - Invitation to high school reunion, 1992; cuid94 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Ursula Nordstrom, 1976; cuid95 (Box 1)
  - Lillian Hoban studio bulletin board material, circa 1960s-1990s; cuid96 (Box 1)
    Miscellaneous material including correspondence from editors, (includes one Ursula Nordstrom letter, dated October 1, 1969) a partial unidentified, unpublished manuscript, one poster, (slightly torn) "Hooray for Lillian Hoban Books," and other material.
  - Manuscript of Elisa in the Middle, by Johanna Hurwitz, undated; cuid97 (Box 1)
  - Maurice Sendak eulogy for Ruth Krauss, with accompanying letter from HarperCollins, 1993; cuid98 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and clips of reviews., circa 1969; cuid99 (Box 1)
  - Original drafts of speeches, cuid100; 11 folders (Box 1)
    A fragment of a speech, and part of an original Silly Tilly draft and other material.
  - Original sketches for Bedtime for Frances book with Frances depicted as a vole., undated; cuid101 (Box 1)
  - "Ready, Set, Robot," by Phoebe and Lillian Hoban, undated; cuid102 (Box 1)
  - Reference material containing photographs of animals, 1950s-1960s; cuid103 (Box 1)
  - Unpublished manuscript, "Jamie's Socks", undated; cuid104 (Box 1)
- Artwork and writings, 1961-1997; Series II; 14.38; (80 boxes)
  - Frances and Arthur
    - Arthur's Back to School Day, proofs and manuscript, 1996; cuid105 (Box 3 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Birthday Party, manuscript, circa 1997; cuid106 (Box 3 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Birthday Party, proofs and artwork, circa 1997; cuid107 (Box 4)
    - "Arthur's Birthday proofs" envelope [empty], with color drawing on vellum, undated; cuid108 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Camp Out, artwork, circa 1993; cuid109 (Box 6)
    - Arthur's Camp Out, manuscript, artwork, and dummy, circa 1993; cuid110 (Box 6)
    - Arthur's Christmas Cookies, artwork, circa 1972; cuid111 (Box 7)
    - Arthur's Christmas Cookies, dummy and artwork, circa 1972; cuid112 (Box 7)
    - Arthur's Funny Money, artwork, 1981; cuid113 (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Funny Money, artwork and manuscript, 1981; cuid114 (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Great Big Valentine, artwork, circa 1988; cuid115 (Box 9)
    - Arthur's Great Big Valentine, dummy, circa 1988; cuid116 (Box 9)
    - Arthur's Great Big Valentine, manuscript, artwork, and proofs, circa 1988; cuid117 (Box 9)
    - Arthur's Halloween Costume, artwork and manuscript, circa 1984; cuid118 (Box 10)
    - Arthur's Halloween Costume, dummy and artwork, circa 1984; cuid119 (Box 10)
    - Arthur's Honey Bear, artwork, 1972; cuid120 (Box 3 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Honey Bear, proof, manuscript, and dummy, cuid121 (Box 3 (Oversize))
    - Arthur's Loose Tooth, artwork, circa 1985; cuid122 (Box 10)
    - Arthur's Loose Tooth, overlay, proof, and artwork, circa 1985; cuid123 (Box 10)
    - Arthur's Pen Pal, manuscript, circa 1974; cuid124 (Box 4)
    - Arthur's Pen Pal, proofs and artwork, circa 1974; cuid125 (Box 4)
    - Arthur's Pen Pal, proofs and artwork, circa 1974; cuid126 (Box 4)
    - Arthur's Prize Reader, artwork, circa 1978; cuid127 (Box 11)
    - Arthur's Prize Reader, artwork and manuscript, circa 1978; cuid128 (Box 11)
    - Arthur valentine, artwork, undated; cuid129 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Baby Sister for Frances, dummy and artwork, circa 1964; cuid130 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Bargain for Frances, artwork, circa 1970; cuid131 (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Bargain for Frances, artwork and manuscript, circa 1970; cuid132 (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Bedtime for Frances, artwork, circa 1960; cuid133 (Box 13 (Oversize))
    - Best Friends for Frances, artwork, circa 1969; cuid134 (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Birthday for Frances, artwork, circa 1968; cuid135 (Box 13 (Oversize))
    - Birthday for Frances, dummy and artwork, circa 1968; cuid136 (Box 13 (Oversize))
    - Bread and Jam for Frances, dummy and proofs, circa 1964; cuid137 (Box 14 (Oversize))
    - Bread and Jam for Frances, artwork, circa 1964; cuid138 (Box 14 (Oversize))
    - Egg Thoughts and Other Frances Songs, artwork, circa 1964; cuid139 (Box 11)
    - Egg Thoughts and Other Frances Songs, manuscript and artwork, circa 1964; cuid140 (Box 11)
    - Frances, artwork, undated; cuid141; 3 folders (Box 15 (Oversize))
    - Frances, artwork, undated; cuid142 (Box 16 (Broadside))
    - Frances, artwork, undated; cuid143 (Box 17 (Broadside))
  - Works with Miriam Cohen and Johanna Hurwitz
    - Amy Loves the Snow, color separations and artwork, circa 1989; cuid144 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Snow, cover art, circa 1989; cuid145 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Snow, dummy, circa 1989; cuid146 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Snow, original art, circa 1989; cuid147 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Snow, second proof, circa 1989; cuid148 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Bee My Valentine, artwork and dummy, circa 1978; cuid149 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Busy Body Nora, negative print, circa 1976; cuid150 (Box 20)
    - Caps, Hats, Socks and Mittens, cover art, circa 1989; cuid151 (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Caps, Hats, Socks and Mittens, dummy, circa 1989; cuid152 (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Caps, Hats, Socks and Mittens, original art, circa 1989; cuid153; 2 folders (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Charlie the Tramp, cover art work, circa 1966; cuid154 (Box 22 (Oversize))
    - Charlie the Tramp, original art, circa 1966, 1983; cuid155 (Box 22 (Oversize))
      Also includes letter from Scholastic Inc., 1983 February 17.
    - Don't Eat Too Much Turkey, cover art and color proofs, circa 1988; cuid156 (Box 23 (Oversize))
    - Don't Eat Too Much Turkey, original artwork, circa 1988; cuid157 (Box 23 (Oversize))
    - "E" is for Elisa, cover art, circa 1991; cuid158 (Box 24)
    - "E" is for Elisa, original art, circa 1991; cuid159 (Box 24)
    - First Grade Poster, color proof, undated; cuid160 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - First Grade Takes a Test, artwork and dummies, circa 1980; cuid161 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Harry's Song, artwork and dummy, circa 1980; cuid162 (Box 25)
    - I Never Did That Before, artwork and proof, circa 1995; cuid163 (Box 25)
    - It's George, artwork, circa 1989; cuid164 (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - It's George, dummy, circa 1989; cuid165 (Box 26 (Oversize))
    - It's Really Christmas, dummy, circa 1982; cuid166 (Box 27)
    - It's Really Christmas, original art, overlay, and notecard from Greenwillow Books, circa 1982; cuid167 (Box 27)
    - Jim's Dog Muffins, artwork, circa 1984; cuid168 (Box 28 (Oversize))
    - Joe and Betsy the Dinosaur, artwork, circa 1995; cuid169 (Box 29)
    - Joe and Betsy the Dinosaur, dummy, circa 1995; cuid170 (Box 29)
      Pencil, Watercolor
    - Joe and Betsy the Dinosaur, manuscripts and interview, circa 1995; cuid171 (Box 29)
    - Liar, Liar, Pants on Fire, artwork, circa 1985; cuid172 (Box 30)
    - Liar, Liar, Pants on Fire, artwork and dummy, circa 1985; cuid173 (Box 30)
    - Liar, Liar, Pants on Fire, original art, circa 1985; cuid174 (Box 31 (Oversize))
    - Like You and Me, artwork, circa 1985-1994; cuid175 (Box 32)
    - Like You and Me, dummies, circa 1985-1994; cuid176 (Box 32)
    - Like You and Me, proofs, 1985-1994; cuid177 (Box 32)
    - Little Bear Sleeping, artwork, circa 1991; cuid178 (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - Little Bear Sleeping, dummies, circa 1991; cuid179 (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - The Little Brute Family, artwork and proof, circa 1966; cuid180 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - New Neighbors For Nora, cover art, circa 1979; cuid181 (Box 24)
    - New Neighbors For Nora, original art, circa 1979; cuid182 (Box 24)
    - No Good at Art, artwork and dummies, circa 1980; cuid183 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Nora and Mrs. Mind-Your-Own-Business, original art, circa 1977; cuid184 (Box 24)
    - Nora and Mrs. Mind-Your-Own-Business, original art, circa 1977; cuid185 (Box 24)
    - The Real Skin Rubber Monster, artwork and dummy, circa 1990; cuid186 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Russell and Elisa, cover art, circa 1989; cuid187 (Box 35)
    - Russell and Elisa, original art, circa 1989; cuid188 (Box 35)
    - Russell and Elisa, original art, circa 1989; cuid189 (Box 35)
    - Russell Rides Again, cover art, circa 1985; cuid190 (Box 36)
    - Russell Rides Again, cover proof, circa 1985; cuid191 (Box 36)
    - Russell Rides Again, dummy proof, circa 1985; cuid192 (Box 36)
    - Russell Rides Again, letter from William Morrow & Co. Inc., circa 1985; cuid193 (Box 36)
    - Russell Rides Again, original art, circa 1985; cuid194 (Box 36)
    - Say Hello Venessa, original art and cover art, circa 1979; cuid195 (Box 37)
      Also includes a letter from Holiday House, 23 May 1980.
    - See You In Second Grade, artwork, circa 1989; cuid196 (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - See You Tomorrow Charles, artwork, circa 1983; cuid197 (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - The Sorely Trying Day, cover art, circa 1964; cuid198; 4 folders (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - The Sorely Trying Day, cover art, circa 1964; cuid199 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - The Sorely Trying Day, original art, circa 1964; cuid200 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - The Sorely Trying Day, proof, circa 1964; cuid201 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Starring First Grade, original art and dummy, circa 1985; cuid202 (Box 40)
    - Start Reading Poster, color proof, circa 1991; cuid203 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - The Stone Doll of Sister Brute, artwork, dummy, cover proof, and galley proof, circa 1968; cuid204 (Box 28 (Oversize))
    - The Sugar Snow Spring, dummies and manuscripts, circa 1973; cuid205 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - The Sugar Snow Spring, original artwork, circa 1973; cuid206 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - The Sugar Snow Spring, proofs, circa 1973; cuid207 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Super Duper Teddy, cover art, circa 1980s; cuid208 (Box 24)
    - Super Duper Teddy, original art, circa 1980; cuid209 (Box 24)
    - Turtle Spring, color separations with original art, circa 1978; cuid210 (Box 42)
    - Turtle Spring, dummy, circa 1978; cuid211 (Box 42)
    - When I Am Big, cover art, circa 1965; cuid212 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - When I Am Big, dummy, circa 1965; cuid213 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - When I Am Big, original art, circa 1965; cuid214 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - When I Am Big, proofs, circa 1965; cuid215 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - When Will I Read?, artwork, dummy, and proof, circa 1977; cuid216 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - Will I Have a Friend?, artwork and dummy, circa 1967; cuid217 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - Will You Be My Valentine?, dummy, circa 1992; cuid218 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Will You Be My Valentine?, artwork, circa 1992; cuid219 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - A Wolf of my Own, dummy, circa 1969; cuid220 (Box 45)
    - A Wolf of my Own, color art, original art, and proof, circa 1969; cuid221 (Box 45)
  - Other works
    - Amy Loves the Rain, artwork and dummy, 1989; cuid222 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Sun, artwork, 1988; cuid223 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Sun, proof, dummy, and mansucript, 1988; cuid224 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Wind, artwork, 1988; cuid225 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Amy Loves the Wind, dummy and manuscript, 1988; cuid226 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Atilla The Angry, dummy and original artwork, 1985; cuid227 (Box 47)
    - Awful Thursday, artwork, 1979; cuid228; 2 folders (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Balancing Girl, artwork, 1981; cuid229 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Balancing Girl, dummy and correspondence, 1981; cuid230 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Best Friends, artwork, 1971; cuid231 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Best Friends, cover proof, circa 1971; cuid232 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Best Friends, galleys and dummy, 1971; cuid233 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - The Big Hello, artwork, 1976; cuid234 (Box 49 (Oversize))
    - The Big Hello, dummy and cover art, 1976; cuid235 (Box 49 (Oversize))
    - The Big Kite Contest, artwork and correspondence, 1980; cuid236 (Box 50 (Oversize))
    - Big Little Lion, artwork, proof and dummy, 1997; cuid237 (Box 50 (Oversize))
    - Big Little Lion, proofs, 1997; cuid238 (Box 50 (Oversize))
      Also contains proofs of Big Little Otter that are attatched to Big Little Lion.
    - Big Little Otter, proofs, correspondence, and manuscript., 1997; cuid239 (Box 50 (Oversize))
      Additional Big Little Otter proofs are attached to Big Little Lion proofs.
    - The Big Seed, artwork, 1992; cuid240 (Box 49 (Oversize))
    - The Brave Little Tailor, artwork, 1990; cuid241 (Box 51)
    - The Case of the Two Masked Robbers, artwork, 1986; cuid242 (Box 52)
    - The Case of the Two Masked Robbers, proofs, galley, and dummy, 1986; cuid243 (Box 52)
    - The Day the Teacher went Bananas, artwork, and dummy, 1984; cuid244 (Box 49 (Oversize))
    - Emmet Otter's Jug Band Christmas, artwork and dummy, 1971; cuid245 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Esmé, comic strip proofs, undated; cuid246; 2 folders (Box 15 (Oversize))
    - Esmé, comic strip proofs, undated; cuid247 (Box 54 (broadside))
    - Ever Clever Elisa, cover art, 1997; cuid248 (Box 47)
    - A Gift-Bear For The King, artwork, 1966; cuid249 (Box 55 (Oversize))
    - A Gift-Bear For The King, dummy and proofs, 1966; cuid250 (Box 55 (Oversize))
    - Goodnight, artwork, circa 1966; cuid251 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Goodnight, dummies and correspondence, cuid252 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Goodnight, proof, 1966; cuid253 (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Grandparents' House, artwork and dummy, 1984; cuid254 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - Grandparents' House, proofs, 1984; cuid255 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - The Great Big Dummy, artwork, 1979; cuid256 (Box 57)
    - The Great Big Dummy, dummy, proof, and correspondence, 1979; cuid257 (Box 57)
    - Harvey's Hideout, artwork, 1969; cuid258 (Box 53 (Oversize))
    - Henry and the Monsterous Din, cover proof, circa 1966; cuid259 (Box 58 (Broadside))
    - Henry and the Monsterous Din, proof and artwork, 1966; cuid260 (Box 59 (Oversize))
    - Here Come The Raccoons!, mechanicals and correspondence, 1977; cuid261 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - Here We Are, artwork, undated; cuid262 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - Here We Are, dummy, proofs, negatives, and manuscripts, undated; cuid263 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - Here We Are, mechanicals, undated; cuid264 (Box 56 (Oversize))
    - Herman the Loser, artwork, 1961; cuid265 (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - Herman the Loser, cover artwork, circa 1961; cuid266 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Herman the Loser, dummies, 1961; cuid267 (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - Herman the Loser, manuscripts, 1961; cuid268 (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - Herman the Loser, artwork, circa 1961; cuid269; 3 folders (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - I Don't Care, artwork, 1977; cuid270 (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - I Don't Care, dummy, 1977; cuid271 (Box 60 (Oversize))
      Also includes publisher correspondence and text by Marjorie Weinman Sharmat.
    - I Know Everything About John And He Knows Everything About Me, dummy, 1993; cuid272 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - I Met a Traveler, manuscript, circa 1977; cuid273 (Box 62 (Oversize))
    - I Met a Traveler, proof, circa 1977; cuid274 (Box 62 (Oversize))
    - I'm Gonna Tell Mama, I Want an Iguana, artwork, 1990; cuid275 (Box 63 (Oversize))
    - I'm Gonna Tell Mama I Want an Iguana, dummy and correspondence, 1990; cuid276 (Box 63 (Oversize))
    - I'm Telling You Now, artwork, 1986; cuid277 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - In One Door and Out the Other, artwork, 1969; cuid278 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - In One Door and Out the Other, proof, 1969; cuid279 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - Jim Meets the Thing, dummy, 1981; cuid280 (Box 64)
    - Just Awful, color separations with original art, 1971; cuid281; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - The Laziest Robot in Zone One, artwork, 1983; cuid282 (Box 65 (Oversize))
    - The Laziest Robot in Zone One, manuscript, partial dummy, and galleys, 1983; cuid283 (Box 65 (Oversize))
    - Lily Boop, artwork, 1986; cuid284; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Little Bear Sleeping, artwork, circa 1991; cuid285 (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - London Men and English Men, cover art and production artwork, 1962; cuid286 (Box 67 (Oversize))
    - London Men and English Men, proof, dummy, memo, and manuscript, 1962; cuid287 (Box 67 (Oversize))
    - Lost in the Museum, dummy, 1979; cuid288 (Box 68)
    - Make Room for Elisa, artwork, 1993; cuid289 (Box 68)
    - Make Room for Elisa, correspondence and cover art, 1993; cuid290 (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous artwork by Hoban, undated; cuid291; 2 folders (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated, 1987; cuid292 (Box 69 (Oversize))
      Includes Harry's Own, Lizzy Mole, A New Turtle Story, Buzzy Bee, Who's Afraid, Jamie's Sock, two untitled manuscripts, and a letter from E.P. Dutton.
    - Mr. Pig and Family, artwork, 1980; cuid293 (Box 70)
    - Mr. Pig and Family, manuscript, 1980; cuid294 (Box 70)
    - Mr. Pig and Family, matted artwork, 1980; cuid295; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Mister Pig and Sonny Too, artwork and manuscript, 1977; cuid296 (Box 63 (Oversize))
    - The Mole Family's Christmas, artwork and cover art, 1969; cuid297; 2 folders (Box 71 (Oversize))
    - Mouse and His Child, artwork, 1967; cuid298 (Box 59 (Oversize))
    - Mouse and His Child, cover art, map art, and notes, 1967; cuid299 (Box 59 (Oversize))
    - My Dad the Magnificent, dummy, cover art, and correspondence, 1987; cuid300 (Box 72 (Oversize))
    - My Dad the Magnificent, artwork, 1987; cuid301 (Box 72 (Oversize))
    - The New Girl at School, artwork and dummy, 1979; cuid302 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - The New Teacher, dummy and correspondence, 1972; cuid303 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - No No Sammy Crow, artwork, 1981; cuid304 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - No No Sammy Crow, dummy and proofs, 1981; cuid305 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - No No Sammy Crow, manuscript and correspondence, 1981; cuid306 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - No No Sammy Crow, matted artwork, 1981; cuid307 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - Nothing To Do, artwork, 1964; cuid308 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - Nothing To Do, manuscript and dummy, 1964; cuid309 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - Papa's Panda, proof, artwork, and correspondence, 1979; cuid310 (Box 74)
    - Peddling Man, artwork and correspondence, 1961; cuid311 (Box 57)
    - A Plant Called Spot, dummy and artwork, 1994; cuid312 (Box 57)
    - Quick Chick, artwork, dummy, manuscript, and correspondence, 1989; cuid313 (Box 74)
    - Rainy Day Together, artwork and dummy, 1971; cuid314 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Ready Set Robot, artwork, 1982; cuid315 (Box 65 (Oversize))
    - Ready Set Robot, manuscripts, dummys, and proofs, 1982; cuid316 (Box 65 (Oversize))
    - Rip Roaring Russell, artwork, 1986; cuid317 (Box 74)
    - Seymour the Prince, artwork and correspondence, 1979; cuid318 (Box 76)
    - Silly Tilly and the Easter Bunny, artwork, 1987; cuid319 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Silly Tilly and the Easter Bunny, manuscript, dummy, and galley, 1987; cuid320 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Silly Tilly's Thanksgiving Dinner, artwork and manuscript, 1979; cuid321 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Silly Tilly's Thanksgiving Dinner, dummies and proofs, 1979; cuid322 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Silly Tilly's Valentine, manuscript, 1984; cuid323 (Box 74)
    - So What?, artwork and dummy, 1982; cuid324 (Box 63 (Oversize))
    - Some Snow Said Hello, artwork, 1963; cuid325 (Box 77 (Oversize))
    - Some Snow Said Hello, manuscript, camera copy, and artwork, 1963; cuid326 (Box 77 (Oversize))
    - Song in My Drum, artwork, 1961; cuid327 (Box 77 (Oversize))
    - Song in My Drum, artwork and note, 1961; cuid328 (Box 77 (Oversize))
    - Sophie and Gussie, artwork, 1973; cuid329 (Box 76)
    - Sophie and Gussie, artwork and manuscript, 1973; cuid330 (Box 76)
    - Squirrel's Song, artwork and correspondence, 1963; cuid331 (Box 77 (Oversize))
    - Staying up Late, artwork, undated; cuid332 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Stick in the Mud, dummy and artwork, 1977; cuid333 (Box 78)
    - The Story of Bently Beaver, dummy and artwork, 1984; cuid334 (Box 78)
    - The Story of Hester Mouse, proof, 1965; cuid335 (Box 74)
    - Strawberry Dress Escape, dummy and artwork, 1975; cuid336 (Box 79)
    - Tales Of Fuzzy Mouse, artwork, 1988; cuid337 (Box 59 (Oversize))
    - Tales Of Fuzzy Mouse, notes, correspondence, and dummy, 1988; cuid338 (Box 59 (Oversize))
    - Tom and the Two Handles, proofs and negative, 1965; cuid339 (Box 72 (Oversize))
    - Tom and the Two Handles, artwork, 1965; cuid340; 2 folders (Box 72 (Oversize))
    - Tough Eddie, artwork, dummy, and correspondence, 1985; cuid341 (Box 79)
    - Tough Jim, artwork, 1974; cuid342 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Tough Jim, dummy and correspondence, 1974; cuid343 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Ugly Bird, artwork and paperwork, 1969; cuid344 (Box 80 Oversize)
    - Victoria's Castle, artwork, 1966; cuid345 (Box 81 (Oversize))
    - Waiting for Noah, artwork, 1990; cuid346 (Box 81 (Oversize))
    - Waiting for Noah, proofs and dummy, 1990; cuid347 (Box 81 (Oversize))
    - What is a Little? What is a Lot?, dummies, undated; cuid348 (Box 69 (Oversize))
    - Where Does the Teacher Live?, dummy and artwork, 1979; cuid349 (Box 79)